<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nikhil Pawar | Data Analytics Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://nick-2313.github.io/Nikhil-Pawar/</link>
    <description>Professional data analytics portfolio showcasing structured analytical projects, dashboard development, and machine learning applications.</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://nick-2313.github.io/Nikhil-Pawar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://nick-2313.github.io/Nikhil-Pawar/about/</link>
      <guid>https://nick-2313.github.io/Nikhil-Pawar/about/</guid>
      <description>
Data analytics professional with dual degrees in Information Systems from Pace University, New York. Specializing in SQL, Python, dashboard development, and KPI-driven performance analysis to support business decision-making.
      </description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Chatbot Development (LSTM)</title>
      <link>https://nick-2313.github.io/Nikhil-Pawar/post/project-6/</link>
      <guid>https://nick-2313.github.io/Nikhil-Pawar/post/project-6/</guid>
      <description>
Developed a deep learning-based chatbot using Python and LSTM neural networks. Implemented structured intent classification and response modeling to simulate real-world conversational AI systems.
      </description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Global Analysis</title>
      <link>https://nick-2313.github.io/Nikhil-Pawar/post/project-1/</link>
      <guid>https://nick-2313.github.io/Nikhil-Pawar/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>
Built an interactive Tableau dashboard analyzing global COVID-19 deaths, vaccinations, and forecast projections. Processed 600K+ records using SQL and statistical tools to derive actionable insights.
      </description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>IMDb Data Automation</title>
      <link>https://nick-2313.github.io/Nikhil-Pawar/post/project-3/</link>
      <guid>https://nick-2313.github.io/Nikhil-Pawar/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>
Automated IMDb data extraction using Selenium WebDriver. Collected structured movie metadata including titles, ratings, reviews, and runtime for downstream analytical processing.
      </description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Recommendation System</title>
      <link>https://nick-2313.github.io/Nikhil-Pawar/post/project-4/</link>
      <guid>https://nick-2313.github.io/Nikhil-Pawar/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>
Implemented a recommendation engine using Python to model user behavior and predict relevant content through collaborative filtering techniques.
      </description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Revenue Analysis</title>
      <link>https://nick-2313.github.io/Nikhil-Pawar/post/project-5/</link>
      <guid>https://nick-2313.github.io/Nikhil-Pawar/post/project-5/</guid>
      <description>
Conducted structured revenue analysis to evaluate income trends, profitability drivers, and performance metrics supporting data-driven business strategy.
      </description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Sentiment Analysis</title>
      <link>https://nick-2313.github.io/Nikhil-Pawar/post/project-2/</link>
      <guid>https://nick-2313.github.io/Nikhil-Pawar/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>
Performed sentiment analysis on Twitter datasets using natural language processing techniques to evaluate brand perception and customer feedback trends.
      </description>
    </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
