<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Nikhil Pawar</title>
    <link>https://nick-2313.github.io/Nikhil-Pawar/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Nikhil Pawar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nick-2313.github.io/Nikhil-Pawar/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ChatBot</title>
      <link>https://nick-2313.github.io/Nikhil-Pawar/post/project-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nick-2313.github.io/Nikhil-Pawar/post/project-6/</guid>
      <description>Use deep learning to create a chatbot using Python. The information, which includes categories (intents), patterns, and responses, will be used to train the chatbot. In order to determine which category the user&amp;rsquo;s message falls under, I employed a specialized recurrent neural network (LSTM), which will select a random response from a list of options. Link to Github Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Analysis</title>
      <link>https://nick-2313.github.io/Nikhil-Pawar/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nick-2313.github.io/Nikhil-Pawar/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>Created Tableau dashboard that showcases COVID-19 deaths , vaccinations and future projections around the globe. Analysed over 600K+ rows using SAS , SMSS and filtered train and test datasets. Engineered features from the datasets using SQL to quantify variables into meaningful values. Optimized SQL queries , CTEs and Views to obtain total deaths, vaccinations across globe and affected countries. Run forecast and timeseries on dataset. Link to Github Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IMDb Website Automation</title>
      <link>https://nick-2313.github.io/Nikhil-Pawar/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nick-2313.github.io/Nikhil-Pawar/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>Automated IMDb website to collect data for movies. I have used Selenium driver to automate specific selections on website. Collected movie titles, revies, ratings, runtime and converted into CSV file for further analysis.
Link to Github Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recommender system using Python</title>
      <link>https://nick-2313.github.io/Nikhil-Pawar/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nick-2313.github.io/Nikhil-Pawar/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>Many applications exist where websites gather user data and use that data to forecast the preferences of their users. They can then recommend the content they enjoy. Recommender systems are a means to propose or find ideas and products that are related to a user&amp;rsquo;s particular way of thinking. Link to Github Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revenue Analysis</title>
      <link>https://nick-2313.github.io/Nikhil-Pawar/post/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nick-2313.github.io/Nikhil-Pawar/post/project-5/</guid>
      <description>revenue refers to income, sales or turnover, monetary units or just plain cash. This gives us an understanding of what revenue analysis entails. It is a purposeful, thorough, and well-researched report that includes income information for all business activities. This can include sales (of goods and services), expenses, earnings, and other elements. Business analysis of revenue is crucial. You can use it to make sure your plans and strategies stay on track with your objective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentimental Analysis</title>
      <link>https://nick-2313.github.io/Nikhil-Pawar/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nick-2313.github.io/Nikhil-Pawar/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>Studied sentiments of users from tweets. In business use case, organizations utilize it to create their plans, comprehend how customers feel about their products or brands, how people react to their advertising campaigns or new product introductions, and determine why some products aren&amp;rsquo;t purchased by consumers. Link to Github Repository</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
